Guide to the Map Collection, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Map Collection, Yale University, records
1906-2014
RU 739
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
8.77
(15 boxes)
The records consist of correspondence and administrative records of the curator of the Map Collection at Yale University Library. Also included are photographs of Map Collection materials and staff.
Yale University. Library
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 32-D (YRG 32-D), Records of Yale school and departmental libraries and collections.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence and administrative records of the curator of the Map Collection at Yale University Library. Also included are photographs of Map Collection materials and staff.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Libraries -- Special collections; Map collections; Maps; Yale University. Library
- Administrative files and correspondence of the curator, 1906-1972; Accession 1987-A-006
  Conditions Governing Access
  The materials are open for research.
  - Elson Beecher, 1906-1912 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Winfield Shiras, 1934-1936
    - A - B (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - D - E - F - G (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - H - K (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Library of Congress (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - M - N - O (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - P - R - S (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - T - V - W - Y (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Samuel Thorne, 1938-1942
    - A - B (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - C (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - D - G (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - F - G (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - H - I (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - J - K (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - L - M (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - N - O (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - P (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - R - S (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - T - U - V (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - W - Y (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Alexander O. Victor, 1942-1972
    - A (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - B (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - C - D (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - E - F - G (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - H - I - J (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - K - L - M (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - N - O - P (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - S - T - U (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - V - W (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - 1961-1963 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - 1964 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - 1965 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - 1966 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - 1967 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - 1968 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - 1969 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - 1970-1972 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Administrative Files
    - Daily Log, Summer 1960 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Daily Logs, Record of bills, 1960-1964 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Daily Log, Summer 1964 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Daily Log, Summer 1966 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Exhibition labels, pre-June 1964 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Karpinsky Collection, 1932 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Janet Murdoch, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Portolan Charts, XV-XVIII (centuries) exhibition information, undated (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Bursary students/information, 1961-1962 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Bursary students/individual records, 1961-1962 (Box 4, Folder 48)
- Map Collection photographs, Circa 1990s; Accession 2011-A-010
  - Collection materials and staff, circa 1990s (Box 1)
- Records, 1927-1935, 1973-2014; Accession 2018-A-030
  - Accession records, 1975-2002 (Box 1, Folder 1-4)
  - Accession records, 1975-2002 (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
  - Account deposits, 1991-1997 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Action plans-Map Collection, 1996-1997 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Africa maps, 1997-2001 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Africa maps-Norwich Collection, Stanford, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Alexandria digital library, 1994-1996 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Anne Soccie records, 2001-2002 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Annual reports, 1995-1999 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Annual statistics, 2004-2005 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Antique maps-Barron, 2003-2004 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Beinecke-Western Americana, 1996-1997 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Budget
    - 1998-2000 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - 2004 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - 2005 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - 2006 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - 2007 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - 2007-2008 (Box 3, Folder 16-17)
    - 2008-2009 (Box 3, Folder 18-19)
    - 2009-2010 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Cartobibliographies, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Cataloging
    - 1998-2003 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - 2006-2007 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Circulation, 2009 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Collection care, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Collection development, 2008 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Collection lists, 1935 (Box 4, Folder 3-4)
  - Conservation, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence
    - 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - A-G, 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - H-N, 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - O-Z, 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - A-G (except Arader and Arkway), 1984-1985 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Arader and Arkway, 1984-1985 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - H-N, 1984-1985 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - O-Z, 1984-1985 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - A-G, 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - H-N, 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - O-Z, 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - A-G, 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - H-N, 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - O-Z, 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - A-G, 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - H-N, 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - O-Z, 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - A-G, 1988-1989 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - H-N, 1988-1989 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - O-Z, 1988-1989 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - A-G, 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - H-N, 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - O-Z, 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - A-G, 1990-1991 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - H-N, 1990-1991 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - O-Z, 1990-1991 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - A-G, 1991-1992 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Acquisitions, 1991-1992 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - 1997-1998 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Joan Swanekamp, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - County atlases, Undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Crown Collection, 1927, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Curiosities, 2001-2004 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Defense Mapping Agency, 1983-1990 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Development, 2011-2013 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Digitizing maps, 1998-2000 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Donation of Denyse E. Reid, 1996-1997 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Donations, 2006-2010 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Duplicate maps for sale, 1973-1981 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - East View Cartographic, 2005 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Egypt maps, Undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Endowments (McCorkle), 1994 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Exhibit loans, 2007-2008 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Ford family gift, 2006-2010 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Gifts-requirements, 1995-1997 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - GIS data, 2000-2002 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - GIS Day, 2014 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - GIS web page, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - GIS-Yale, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Globes, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Grants, 2003-2008 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Hood Art Museum-Dartmouth, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Historic New Haven/Historic China-GIS, 2003 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Imaginary maps, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Inventory checks, 2006 (Box 5, Folder 28-33)
  - Inventories-curator's office, 1978-2005 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Inventories-found maps, atlases and uncatalogued maps, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Journals-remote sensing, Undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Lada Mocarski collection
    - Slides, Undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Slides and inventory, Undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Lanman collection
    - Appraisal, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Contents, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1987-2003 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Gift records, 1978-1988 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Japanese and Chinese maps and prints, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Malcolm Edgerton, 1988-1998 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Maps, 1988-1998 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Library map prize, 1980-2012 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Listing of Dutch Atlases and Maps at Yale-volume 1, Circa 1960s (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Listing of Dutch Atlases and Maps at Yale-volume 2, Circa 1960s (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Loans-Mount Holyoke College Art Museum, 1995-1996 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Loans-Yale Art Gallery, 1996-2001 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - LSF-Map Collection, 2000-2001 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Map Center-configuration, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Map Collection-funds, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Map purchases, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Map reclamation, 2006-2007 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Map room manual, 1980-1989 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Map storage, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Memorandum, 1986-1992 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Microfilm check, 2006 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Microfilm inventory, 2005 (Box 7, Folder 1-6)
  - Microfilm prints identified as manuscript maps, 2006 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Missing atlases, Undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Miniature maps, Undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Missing maps and prints, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Missing maps, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Missing maps, 2006 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Monumenta Cartographica Neerlandica, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Mudd atlases-inventory, 2005 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Orbis-inventory, Undated (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Orders
    - Correspondence
      - 1980-1982 (Box 7, Folder 16)
      - 1982-1984 (Box 7, Folder 17)
      - 1984 July (Box 7, Folder 18)
      - 1985 July (Box 7, Folder 19)
      - 1986-1987 (Box 7, Folder 20)
      - 1987-1988 (Box 7, Folder 21)
      - 1988-1989 (Box 7, Folder 22)
      - 1989-1990 (Box 7, Folder 22a)
    - Paid or pre-paid
      - 1984 July (Box 7, Folder 23)
      - 1985 July (Box 7, Folder 24)
      - 1986-1987 (Box 7, Folder 25)
      - 1987-1988 (Box 7, Folder 26)
      - 1988-1989 (Box 7, Folder 27)
      - 1989-1990 (Box 7, Folder 28)
      - 1989-1996 (Box 7, Folder 29)
      - 1997-1998 (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - 1998 (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - 1998-1999 (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - 1999 (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - 2000-2001 (Box 8, Folder 5)
      - 2001-2002 (Box 8, Folder 6)
      - 2002-2003 (Box 8, Folder 7)
      - 2003-2007 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Received
      - 1980-1982 (Box 8, Folder 9)
      - 1982-1984 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Other libraries, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Patron log
    - 2007-2009 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - 2009-2012 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Permissions to pubish, 2004-2010 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Purchases
    - General
      - 1993-1996 (Box 8, Folder 15)
      - 1997-2005 (Box 8, Folder 16-17)
    - W. Graham Arader, 1987-1990 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Richard B. Arkway, 1993-1995 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Roderick Barron, 2004-2006 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Erisau, 2001-2002 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Howard H. Holtzmann, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Martayan Lan, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - David M. Lesser, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - M. Moliero Editor, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Rick Prelinger, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Publicity, 1999 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Rare map transit and access log, 2006-2007 (Box 9, Folder 1-2)
  - Rare map transit and access log, 2008-2014 (Box 9, Folder 3-4)
  - Road map collectors, 1984-1997 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Reprographic orders, 2003-2011 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Reprographic orders, 2004-2006 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Reprographic orders, 2008-2015 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Renovation photographs, Undated (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Requests for data sets, 2002-2011 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Sanborn maps, 1996-1997 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Slavonic papers, 1996 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Security Committee, 2003-2008 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Soviet maps, 1966-1981 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Stolen maps, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Survey, 2007 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Teaching about maps, 1996 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Training-GIS, 2009 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Transfers from the Map Collection, 1988-1989 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - USGS maps, 2003-2004 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Utopia maps, 1999 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Vinland map, 1996-2000 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Wall maps for teaching, Undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Walling, Henry F.-roll maps, Undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - White Brothers-New Haven and Shoreline Property maps inventory, Undated (Box 10, Folder 9)